<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-05T19:09:01+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Lubbock Coding Academy Helps Locals Chart New Path</title><link href="/blog/news/lubbock-coding-academy-helps-locals-chart-new-path/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lubbock Coding Academy Helps Locals Chart New Path" /><published>2020-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/news/lubbock-coding-academy-helps-locals-chart-new-path</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/news/lubbock-coding-academy-helps-locals-chart-new-path/">&lt;p&gt;When was the last time you thought about your potential? It seems like after kindergarten graduation, school and life stopped asking what you wanted to be and instead started telling you what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like most millennials, you probably aren’t happy with your current job and don’t see much potential for upward mobility or meaningful contribution… you are not alone. Millennials feel stuck - longing to create and contribute in meaningful ways but lacking the technical skills and experience to land high-paying, in-demand jobs. The disparity is even greater in non-urban areas like Lubbock, where education funding and offerings tend to lag behind larger cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequences of lower quality education lead to less developed workforce skillsets and force local employers to recruit “out of town” talent to fill the higher-paying, more skilled technology jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These developer roles offer compensation, lifestyle and meaningful contribution opportunities that are often ideal for millennials and contain the ingredients for long, happy and fulfilling careers. &lt;strong&gt;The U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics reports that the median salary for web developers was $110,000 (May 2018) and the employment of software developers is projected to grow 24% between 2016 - 2026.&lt;/strong&gt; Attuned to employer demand, the rise of coding academies has begun to bridge the ‘skills gap’ in preparing people for careers in tech. However, these coding schools have been exclusive to densely populated metroplexes allotting little regard for equally talented, less industrious areas that have served as the backbone of America’s economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of innovative education opportunities and computer programming skill sets continue to place rural workers and employers in a bind. Workers are willing to learn new skills to qualify for jobs in technology, but local employers can’t front the cost of building and teaching a curriculum that delivers the necessary skills for success in these roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sensing rising frustrations and witnessing a constant &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.listenmoneymatters.com/what-is-brain-drain/&quot;&gt;“Brain Drain”&lt;/a&gt; of local Lubbock talent to urban cities, Texas Tech commissioned Austin Coding Academy to equip Lubbock area workers with the coding skills to win rewarding careers in technology here at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lubbock Coding Academy (now a partner with the Lubbock Economic Development Association (LEDA), South Plains College and Texas Tech University) provides ‘full-stack’ coding education and skill development through part-time, in-person classes allowing students to keep their day jobs while gaining the skills to upgrade careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 32-week program meets twice a week in the evenings and consists of four 8 week classes taught by full-time developers who know exactly what it takes to succeed in a career in tech. Students have access to unlimited one-on-one tutoring sessions, Saturday study groups and initiate countless meetups at local libraries and coffee shops to understand the nuances of their new highly valuable skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lubbock Coding Academy’s coding curriculum is completely customized to the request of 12 of Lubbock County’s largest employers (including Tyler Technologies, SitePro, Texas Tech &amp;amp; many others) who as a group have stated &lt;strong&gt;they plan to hire 50 - 100 developers in each of the next five years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lubbock Coding Academy (LCA) graduates are finding themselves in the perfect position to secure these careers thanks to their ‘full-stack’ education and access to LCA’s &lt;strong&gt;Job Placement Program&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition to the 32-week curriculum, LCA offers students a free four-week job placement course where they work on best practices for resume building, participate in mock interviews and whiteboarding sessions, and attend networking events with local employers and LCA partners. Additionally, LCA’s placement and partnerships department takes initiative to connect recent graduates with jobs in technology and boasts a &lt;strong&gt;91% placement rating&lt;/strong&gt; graduating alumni to tech giants like Facebook, Amazon, and IBM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February of 2019, the first group of 20 Lubbock County residents began their journey to a better life. After completing all four instructional modules and the Job Placement module at the Texas Tech Innovation Hub, &lt;strong&gt;every Lubbock Coding Academy program graduate has been successfully placed in a new career in technology.&lt;/strong&gt; Since the first cohort launch in February 2019, four more cohorts have launched in Lubbock’s Full Stack Web Development Program and are on their way to new careers in technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LCA has seemed to strike a chord in Lubbock County. People of all types are excited about becoming students again and improving their skills and career possibilities. Local officials and employers are also backing the LCA partnership as a means to enhance a workforce that has previously been underestimated by outside investors. In time, Lubbock may prove to be fertile ground for new business and start-up investment, and now with a growing population of software developers and computer programmers, they won’t have to go far to find good help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a Lubbock County resident who is looking to break away from the pack and chart your own path, you may be a good candidate for a career in technology through Lubbock Coding Academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Lubbock Coding Academy’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://lubbockcodingacademy.com/web-dev/&quot;&gt;web development curriculum&lt;/a&gt; and class start dates, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lubbockcodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;apply online&lt;/a&gt;. We are currently enrolling students for our next cohort.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Lubbock Coding Academy is helping the people of Lubbock launch new careers in Lubbock's growing technology industry.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY &amp;amp; WP ENGINE LAUNCH WORDPRESS FUNDAMENTALS COURSE AND JOB OPPORTUNITIES</title><link href="/blog/press-release/austin-coding-academy-wp-engine-partnership/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY &amp; WP ENGINE LAUNCH WORDPRESS FUNDAMENTALS COURSE AND JOB OPPORTUNITIES" /><published>2019-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/press-release/ustin-coding-academy-wp-engine-launch-support-wordpress-fundamentals-course-and-job-opportunities</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/press-release/austin-coding-academy-wp-engine-partnership/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE: 10/28/2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Austin, TX – October 2019:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Austin Coding Academy (ACA) and WP Engine today announced an ongoing collaboration to launch an in-person&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/courses/wordpress-fundamentals/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;WordPress Fundamentals course&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;to train students in core WordPress elements and develop the technical proficiencies necessary to become a technical support specialist with WP Engine. In addition to providing this technical training, WP Engine will guarantee an interview with every student who completes the course to explore career possibilities with WP Engine. Qualified graduates will interview at WP Engine for an L1 Support Technician position. All WP Engine employees will enjoy competitive compensation, health benefits, paid time off, family leave, 401k with match, equity, ongoing training &amp;amp; development and much more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Central to Austin Coding Academy’s mission is continuing to increase access to careers in technology in Austin through thoughtful technical training and to create innovative employment and training solutions for tech companies. “This course, in collaboration with WP Engine, is an opportunity to train for an in-demand skill while also providing students with a unique opportunity to launch their career with a top tech company here in Austin,” says Austin Coding Academy CEO, Chris Lofton. “We’re also excited to collaborate with WP Engine to provide an innovative hiring solution to fuel their continued growth.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We are excited to collaborate with Austin Coding Academy,” said Brian Ferguson, Senior Director, Talent Acquisition at WP Engine. “We feel this partnership will help build a community of WordPress experts while adding another channel for growth for our Customer Experience team.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;WP Engine and Austin Coding Academy will be launching the first WordPress Fundamentals cohort in early 2020, with classes to be held at Austin Coding Academy – Highland Campus (314 E Highland Mall Blvd, Austin, TX 78752). The key features of the program include:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;10 weeks of instruction, consisting of part-time, evening courses taught by a professional WordPress Developer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unlimited tutoring included in tuition for all students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A practical, project-based curriculum that covers a wide range of WordPress fundamentals, as well as the opportunity to interface with WP Engine Recruiters and interview for a Technical Support role&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information, contact the above representatives, visit the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/courses/wordpress-fundamentals/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;WordPress Fundamentals Course Page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;or join Austin Coding Academy and WP Engine at the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/austin-coding-academywp-engine-launch-event-happy-hour-wp-engine-tickets-78066889167&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;WordPress Fundamentals Launch Event&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;on Thursday, November 14th at WP Engine (504 Lavaca St, Austin, TX 78701).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eric Jones, VP, Global Communications, WP Engine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:press@wpengine.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;press@wpengine.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chris Lofton, CEO, Austin Coding Academy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:clofton@austincodingacademy.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;clofton@austincodingacademy.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Austin Coding Academy:&lt;/strong&gt; Austin Coding Academy is Austin’s source for innovative tech talent and education. Our mission is to make careers in technology accessible to everyone through practical and equitable technical training, and to provide innovative solutions and training to tech companies. Learn more about ACA here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;https://austincodingacademy.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About WP Engine:&lt;/strong&gt; WP Engine is the WordPress Digital Experience Platform that gives companies of all sizes the agility, performance, intelligence, and integrations they need to drive their business forward faster. WP Engine’s combination of tech innovation and an award-winning team of WordPress experts are trusted by over 120,000 customers across 150 countries to provide counsel and support, helping brands create world-class digital experiences. Founded in 2010, WP Engine is headquartered in Austin, Texas, and has offices in Brisbane, Australia; Limerick, Ireland; London, England; Omaha, Nebraska; San Antonio, Texas; and San Francisco, California.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Austin Coding Academy and WP Engine today announced an ongoing collaboration to launch an in-person “WordPress Fundamentals” course to train students in the technical proficiencies necessary to become a technical support specialist with WP Engine and provide a guaranteed interview. Learn more:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TEXAS TECH UNIVERSITY &amp;amp; AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY PARTNER TO LAUNCH TEXAS TECH UNIVERSITY CODING ACADEMY</title><link href="/blog/press-release/texas-tech-and-austin-coding-academy-partner-to-launch-texas-tech-university-coding-academy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TEXAS TECH UNIVERSITY &amp; AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY PARTNER TO LAUNCH TEXAS TECH UNIVERSITY CODING ACADEMY" /><published>2019-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/press-release/texas-tech-university-austin-coding-academy-partner-to-launch-texas-tech-university-coding-academy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/press-release/texas-tech-and-austin-coding-academy-partner-to-launch-texas-tech-university-coding-academy/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE: 9/17/2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Austin, TX – September 2019:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Texas Tech University and Austin Coding Academy (ACA) today announced an ongoing partnership to launch “Texas Tech University Coding Academy”, a part-time web development program that prepares students for careers as web developers and software engineers. Texas Tech University Coding Academy will launch its first cohort at Texas Tech University at Highland Lakes in early 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Austin Coding Academy’s mission is to increase access to careers in technology through thoughtful technical training and to create innovative employment, training, and education solutions to meet the needs of the growing tech industry. “Texas Tech Coding Academy represents a great opportunity for Austin Coding Academy to partner with one of Texas’ premier public universities to provide an innovative education solution for communities around the state,’’ says Austin Coding Academy CEO, Chris Lofton. “We’re looking forward to launching the program at Texas Tech University at Highland Lakes, and finding ways that we can make Texas Tech Coding Academy work for the community of Marble Falls and surrounding areas.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Texas Tech University has offered academic degree programs in Marble Falls for several years. However, the certificate programs being taught through the Texas Tech University Coding Academy is a new offering. It is exciting to be able to offer this opportunity for individuals in the Highland Lakes area,” says Dr. Melanie Hart, Vice Provost for eLearning and Academic Partnerships at Texas Tech University.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Texas Tech University and Austin Coding Academy will be launching the first Texas Tech University Coding Academy cohort in early 2020, with classes to be held at Texas Tech University at Highland Lakes (806 Steve Hawkins Pkwy, Marble Falls, TX 78654). The key features of the program include:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;32 week, part-time instruction developing Full Stack Web Development skills, with a focus on JavaScript&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unlimited tutoring included in tuition for all students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A practical, project-based curriculum that prepares students to be professional web developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information, contact the below representatives, or join Austin Coding Academy and Texas Tech University at a public signing on September 18th at Texas Tech University at Highland Lakes or visit texastechcodingacademy.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clay Taylor Ed.D, Senior Director, Texas Tech University&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Clay.Taylor@ttu.edu&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clay.Taylor@ttu.edu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chris Lofton, CEO, Austin Coding Academy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:clofton@austincodingacademy.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;clofton@austincodingacademy.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Texas Tech University:&lt;/strong&gt; The Texas Tech University System was formed in 1996 and formally established by the State of Texas three years later in 1999. Since its inception, the TTU System has emerged as one of the top public university systems in the nation and is a dynamic force in higher education. Today, the TTU System consists of four component institutions and operates at multiple campuses and academic sites across the state and globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Austin Coding Academy:&lt;/strong&gt; Austin Coding Academy is Austin’s source for innovative tech talent and education. Our mission is to make careers in technology accessible to everyone through practical and equitable technical training and to provide innovative solutions and training to tech companies. Learn more about ACA here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;https://austincodingacademy.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Texas Tech University and Austin Coding Academy (ACA) today announced an ongoing partnership to launch “Texas Tech University Coding Academy”, a part-time web development program that prepares students for careers as web developers and software engineers. Texas Tech University Coding Academy will launch its first cohort at Texas Tech University at Highland Lakes in early 2020.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Austin Coding Academy Student Highlight: Greg Swan</title><link href="/blog/student-highlight/greg-swan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Austin Coding Academy Student Highlight: Greg Swan" /><published>2019-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/student-highlight/austin-coding-academy-student-highlight-greg-swan</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/student-highlight/greg-swan/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;get-to-know-austin-coding-academy-graduate-greg-swan&quot;&gt;Get to know Austin Coding Academy graduate Greg Swan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Austin Coding Academy, we take pride in the success that our students and graduates achieve. Every month we look to highlight at least one of our graduates and let the world know about what they’re doing in their new careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, we caught up with Austin Coding Academy graduate &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Greg Swan&lt;/a&gt;, who accepted a job as a Web Developer at Kinetic Theory in Austin after finishing our Full Stack Web Development Track in 2018. Greg now works as a Web Application Developer with OpenSymmetry. Here’s what he had to say about his experience as an Austin Coding Academy student:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-austin-coding-academy-prepare-you-for-the-job-market&quot;&gt;How did Austin Coding Academy prepare you for the job market?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACA prepared me for the job market the way a high school teacher prepares you for college; they gave me a solid foundation of knowledge, taught me what not to do, and consistently reminded me that there was a job out there for me if I was willing to put in the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;did-aca-help-you-on-the-job-search&quot;&gt;Did ACA help you on the job search?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! Chris Lofton was a great a help as far as finding and landing my first job. He recommended me to so many employers, and was a big part of how I got my initial interview for my current position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;any-advice-for-current-or-future-aca-students&quot;&gt;Any advice for current or future ACA students?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gcswan.github.io/Resume/&quot;&gt;A portfolio&lt;/a&gt; is helpful and can help you find a job, but I think it was also helpful to build one more website. &lt;strong&gt;Also: the more you code, the better you get.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;share-a-fun-fact-about-yourself&quot;&gt;Share a fun fact about yourself.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wake up in the middle of the night and eat ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-to-learn-more&quot;&gt;Want to learn more?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about why Austin Coding Academy is the perfect place to launch your coding career, download our course guide below or &lt;a href=&quot;https://acaappointment.acuityscheduling.com/schedule.php?appointmentType=1406673&quot;&gt;schedule a Q&amp;amp;A with us today&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sudent-highlight" /><summary type="html">This month, we caught up with ACA graduate Greg Swan, who accepted a job as a Web Developer at Kinetic Theory in Austin after finishing the JavaScript track. Greg now works as a Web Application Developer with OpenSymmetry. Here's what he had to say about his experience as an Austin Coding Academy student:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">4 Ways a Coding Bootcamp is Worth It</title><link href="/blog/web-development/4-ways-a-coding-bootcamp-is-worth-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 Ways a Coding Bootcamp is Worth It" /><published>2019-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/web-development/4-ways-a-coding-bootcamp-is-worth-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/web-development/4-ways-a-coding-bootcamp-is-worth-it/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-after-graduation-4-ways-a-coding-boot-camp-is-worth-it&quot;&gt;What’s After Graduation? 4 Ways a Coding Boot Camp Is Worth It&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since coding academies have become an increasingly visible part of the tech landscape over the last half-decade, more schools have cropped up with more coders graduating every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While job placement statistics for bootcamp graduates have been fantastic since the schools came into existence, there’s still a growing sense among some that enrolling may not be worth it. With so much new popularity, it’s fair to ask if a coding boot camp is worth it. In fact, we’re going to ask it (and explore it) even more directly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has the market for coders reached saturation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to answer this question, we’re going to explore what life is really like after graduating from a coding boot camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a coding bootcamp ourselves, this information is extremely important to us, so we make sure our sources on the tech industry and employment statistics are as thorough and current as possible. So let’s see why coding bootcamp might be right it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;coding-graduates-make-excellent-money&quot;&gt;Coding Graduates Make Excellent Money&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding bootcamps are an investment. There’s a lot of earning potential afterwards, but there’s also the cost of tuition to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, getting a bachelor’s in computer science from a university is a four-year process, and it doesn’t come cheap. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.collegecalc.org/majors/computer-science/&quot;&gt;estimated average for a four-year computer science degree&lt;/a&gt; is $167,968. Associate programs take two years, and the average cost is $41,568. By comparison, a coding academy is a fraction of the cost, and the courses span weeks or months instead of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even though coding classes are cheaper and faster, the earning potential is the same. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursereport.com/blog/salaries-after-coding-bootcamp&quot;&gt;study by Course Report&lt;/a&gt; found that the average bootcamp graduate makes a starting salary of $70,698 annually. Plus, as the tech industry continues to grow, that earning potential will keep growing with it. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://money.usnews.com/careers/best-jobs/software-developer/salary&quot;&gt;median pay&lt;/a&gt; for software engineers is already $101,790, and the top 25% of earners make an average of $128,960. So if you’re in it for the money, going to a coding bootcamp is definitely worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bootcamp-graduates-get-hired&quot;&gt;Bootcamp Graduates Get Hired&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, starting salaries don’t apply to graduates who don’t get hired, but coding bootcamp graduates have around a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hyperiondev.com/index.php/2019/03/04/will-i-get-a-job-after-a-coding-bootcamp/&quot;&gt;90% job placement average&lt;/a&gt;. A huge portion of these jobs exists because of the healthy growth in the programming industry. In fact, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/software-developers.htm&quot;&gt;United States Bureau of Labor&lt;/a&gt; predicts that the availability of software developer jobs is growing at 24%, which is way higher than jobs in other industries. Because the tech industry and the coding industry are growing together, they both get perks from finding job opportunities with new graduates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those hiring statistics only improve when the coding bootcamp has industry connections (like us). At Austin Coding Academy, we stay plugged into the local tech industry to keep expanding our network across the nation. Our curriculum is even built for and with hiring companies, meaning that you learn exactly what you need to get hired after graduating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-coding-bootcamp-sets-you-up-for-many-different-tech-jobs&quot;&gt;A Coding Bootcamp Sets You Up for Many Different Tech Jobs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people worry that certain coding classes will only set you up for certain jobs, but the truth is that a lot of tech jobs require solid coding know-how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Careers can change depending on the company and industry, but our graduates have found career fits as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software engineers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full stack developers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web developers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Product architects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project managers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UX developers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coding Instructors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of versatility in coding, which attracts students from all walks of life. Whether you’re supplementing existing skills, wanting a total career change, or just want to strike out on your own, we help our bootcamp students find opportunities they’ve never thought of before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;important-companies-hire-from-coding-academies&quot;&gt;Important Companies Hire from Coding Academies&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big names in the tech industry recognize the value of bootcamp graduates. Our former students have found work with Dell, IBM, Dosh, Plural Sight, Oracle, Adobe, and more. Or, if you want to go in the opposite direction, start-ups are always looking for fresh talent, to the point where they often hire right out of bootcamps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, 72% of employers find that coding boot camp graduates are just as competent as university graduates. &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.indeed.com/2017/05/02/what-employers-think-about-coding-bootcamp/&quot;&gt;Some hiring managers&lt;/a&gt; even prefer boot camp graduates to university computer science majors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to find a job worth having in the technology industry, you need to learn how to code before you can do much else. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/web-development/&quot;&gt;Full Stack Web Development Program&lt;/a&gt; is designed to teach you the skills you need to ultimately get the job you want. In other words, our job isn’t done until you have your job.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Since coding academies have become an increasingly visible part of the tech landscape over the last half-decade, more schools have cropped up with more coders graduating every year. With so much new popularity, it's fair to ask if a coding boot camp is worth it. In fact, we’re going to ask it (and explore it) even more directly:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">7 Characteristics of a Successful Web Developer</title><link href="/blog/web-development/7-characteristics-of-a-successful-web-developer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 Characteristics of a Successful Web Developer" /><published>2019-04-16T17:53:50+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-16T17:53:50+00:00</updated><id>/blog/web-development/7-characteristics-of-a-successful-web-developer</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/web-development/7-characteristics-of-a-successful-web-developer/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethanstenis/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke Stenis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;graduated from Austin Coding Academy’s Full Stack Web Development program in 2016. Upon graduating, Luke landed a role as an “Implementation Engineer” with Austin-based content production company,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invodo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. During his time at Invodo, Luke also worked as an instructor at ACA, teaching the 10-week “Intro to Web Development” course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke currently works in Salt Lake City, Utah, as a “Digital Analytics Implementation Engineer” with&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PluralSight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there certain characteristics that make you a better web developer than others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking into the tech scene can be very intimidating - it seems like every day there is a trendy new JS library to learn and another class of coding school graduates to compete with. If you spend any time scouring job boards, you’ll also see this reflected in entry-level or junior web development jobs requiring a wider knowledge base from their applicants than in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, naturally, you would think that candidates with the deepest ocean of knowledge would always land the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may come as a surprise to you – as the web developer role spends most of their time in front of a computer screen, handling highly technical issues with complicated code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, I’ve been on both sides of the hiring process for tech roles, and have witnessed the smartest candidates get passed over for someone who is a better “fit” for the role or company. I’ve seen the sharpest web developers crumble and crack under the pressure of deadlines, or lose their patience and professionalism from constructive feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great code doesn’t always translate into a great hire. While it definitely helps, there is more to being a successful web developer than a mind rich in technical knowledge. Here are seven characteristics common in web developers - other than technical skills - who are successful at their job:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-passion-for-knowledge&quot;&gt;A passion for knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/uploads/blog-5-31-17-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology is always evolving, and the skills and abilities needed in today’s tech scene can get outdated quickly. It’s important to have a passion for learning and the desire to keep up with the latest trends. As newer versions of languages, libraries and frameworks roll out, you will be expected to not only know these changes, but be a subject matter expert within your company. Don’t confuse this with technical skills - you can still love to learn without being the sharpest crayon in the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goes beyond a willingness to educate yourself. You should embrace the inevitable challenges that come with the job, and develop a great habit for researching possible solutions. If you love the work and the challenge that it presents, you will be successful at your job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-teammate&quot;&gt;Great teammate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/uploads/blog-5-31-17-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A web developer rarely works alone. Good software is commonly built by a whole development team comprised of many dynamic roles. Being able to take on a team mentality can be critical to the success of a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the immediate team, web developers will also be expected to work with business owners, sales and marketing staff, and other developers outside of the team or company in order to achieve a wider project scope. In these cases, the ability to lead or act as the representative of your team in a meeting or other professional scenario is a soft skill that helps you stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creative-problem-solver&quot;&gt;Creative problem solver&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/uploads/blog-5-31-17-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing code for a software program or designing website from scratch is incredibly difficult – much like trying to solve a complex math equation or write a novel. A great developer thrives on finding ways to make things work, no matter the challenge, and sometimes needs to get creative to find a working solution. You want to try to avoid the phrase “It can’t be done” when you are pitched a new project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great working knowledge of the language or framework you are using is a must. If you understand the limitations or abilities of the code you are using, you can awaken more creative and efficient ideas for solving problems. And the light bulbs will turn on faster and brighter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ability-to-plan-for-everything&quot;&gt;Ability to plan for everything&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/uploads/blog-5-31-17-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than jumping head-first into a project, a wise and cautious web developer will first learn as much as possible about the desired end product. Once this step is completed, the developer will then plan out the entire structure of the project before typing out one line of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a critical step - as one little oversight can throw a project deadline off by weeks or even months. Complete your wireframe the entire site and get approval before creating your first template. Ensure your routes and controllers are properly configured. If you don’t properly plan for as much as possible, you better have…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-debugging-skills&quot;&gt;Great debugging skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/uploads/blog-5-31-17-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my current job, I identify and solve issues on large, e-commerce websites. Basically, I help fix bad code written by their in-house developers that they couldn’t solve themselves. What I found more shocking than how simple the mistakes are – was how often the developers themselves did not know how to properly debug their own mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing and developing code is only part of a web developer’s job. They are also expected to identify the root of a problem quickly and effectively. Instead of spending hours making blind changes, developers need to have a solid handle on the variety of Web Developer Tools provided by modern browsers such as Chrome, Firefox, Safari, and Edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;accelerated-failure-mentality&quot;&gt;“Accelerated Failure” Mentality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/uploads/blog-5-31-17-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fail Fast”, “Fail Better”, “Fail Forward” are all popular mantras used by startups and tech giants in Silicon Valley. If you aren’t failing, you aren’t learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rarely does code get written correctly the first time. This is why we plan for everything and know how to debug anything. It’s important to see bugs and errors in your code as a challenge rather than a sign of defeat. Successful web developers embrace the challenge of failure and tend to bounce back with bigger and better solutions to these problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;business-sense&quot;&gt;Business Sense&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/uploads/blog-5-31-17-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great developer can look beyond the project they are working on and see the big picture for the business. A savvy business sense can lead to new applications or automated processes focused on more saving time and money for a company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to an MBA or a passion for macro-economics to be business-savvy, but showing an interest in areas of the business outside of your direct scope can lead to a better understanding of your company’s big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn’t easy becoming a web developer - and to excel in the industry takes more than an encyclopedia of coding knowledge. There are certain characteristics that successful web developers share not commonly taught in many CS degree programs or coding schools. You need to have a variety of soft skills on top of your technical abilities to stand out in the crowd when applying for a job in the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaching these soft skills is one way our program stands out in the crowd of coding schools. Our program not only teach our students the technical skills every full-stack web developer needs, every campus provide workshops and break-out sessions in order to provide a wider educational foundation in soft skills proven to help any fledgling web developer succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in learning both the hard and soft skills necessary for a successful coding career, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/courses/&quot;&gt;course schedule&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;fill out an application&lt;/a&gt; to save your spot in the next class.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Great code doesn’t always translate into a great hire. While it definitely helps, there is more to being a successful web developer than a mind rich in technical knowledge. Here are seven characteristics common in web developers - other than technical skills - who are successful at their job:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I Left Marketing to Learn Coding – Luke Stenis: Austin Coding Academy Alumni Spotlight</title><link href="/blog/alumni-spotlight/luke-stenis/why-i-left-marketing-to-learn-coding/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I Left Marketing to Learn Coding – Luke Stenis: Austin Coding Academy Alumni Spotlight" /><published>2019-04-13T19:23:55+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T19:23:55+00:00</updated><id>/blog/alumni-spotlight/luke-stenis/why-i-left-marketing-to-learn-coding-luke-stenis-austin-coding-academy-alumni-spotlight</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/alumni-spotlight/luke-stenis/why-i-left-marketing-to-learn-coding/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;self-confessed-austin-coding-academy-brand-fanatic-luke-stenis-on-why-he-decided-to-leave-marketing-learn-coding-and-teach-others-to-code&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-confessed Austin Coding Academy ‘brand fanatic’ Luke Stenis on why he decided to leave marketing, learn coding, and teach others to code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A native of Oklahoma, Luke Stenis originally moved to Austin for grad school. Falling in love with the city - and his future wife - he stayed to start a family, and a career. I asked him what he does for fun. ‘Sunday league soccer with Cameron Road United, the most interesting team in Austin,’ he replies, with a grin. He also plays bass, and has been in several local bands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Receiving a Masters in Advertising from UT’s College of Communications, he dabbled in traditional agency work and media research, finally landing in digital marketing. ‘I enjoyed the challenges of copywriting for the web,’ he says. ‘I loved helping tell marketing stories and drive audience behavior.’ Marketing is a ferocious game, however - the pressure is on to continually upsell and cross-sell campaigns to squeeze out that one last dollar. After eight years, he decided he was done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-i-learned-to-code&quot;&gt;Why I learned to Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Strategy Director, he was working very closely with the Engineering and IT departments, improving the website. Together, they optimized conversion funnels - the advertising term for a customer’s journey from a web search or ad, through an e-commerce website, and finally to a sale. ‘I understood the basics, but was never in the trenches myself,’ he explains. He was tired of continually waiting in a queue for issue tickets to be resolved. ‘I wanted to learn how to solve these UX/UI problems myself’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laid off in March of 2015, he realized he no longer had the ‘bellyfire’ passion for marketing. Tired of his ethics and morals being tested, he longed for ‘a career with long-term stability and a more learning-centric foundation’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-the-decision-to-learn-coding&quot;&gt;Making the Decision to Learn Coding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He used his ‘extensive experience in digital marketing to find ACA via Google search’, he says, laughing. As a young father supporting his family, being able to learn to code without quitting his interim bill-paying job was key. ‘It perfectly fit my lifestyle,’ he explains. ‘The school is flexible but still maintains a high level of authenticity’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Learning how to code and approach problem-solving has changed my life,’ says Luke passionately. His favorite thing about coding is also one of the most frustrating. ‘There are correct ways to do things with code. There are also different ways you use code to solve a problem,’ he explains. ‘Sometimes short term solutions can create long term inefficiencies’. Creating well-constructed projects isn’t just about the code required to make them work straight away. According to Luke, the challenge when approaching code issues is to think long-term, and to fix defects in a way that won’t hinder future improvements or projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thinking-like-a-developerengineer&quot;&gt;Thinking Like a Developer/Engineer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s applying these skills to his life in more than just a work setting. ‘I now approach everything in life like code. Assess the problem, look at the end goal, plan each step, and execute with detail and confidence.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luke is now an instructor at ACA - a career that he loves. He spends his days as a full time developer and spends his evenings paying it forward to students, teaching tAfter meeting the school’s founders, Chris Sica and Luke Filipos, and completing the beginner, intermediate and advanced classes, he ‘became a huge brand fanatic!’ - which appears to be marketing speak for ‘I’m a fan!’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving a stagnant career to learn coding was the best thing Luke says he’s ever done. ‘My life has really come into focus and its path has never been more clear’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;there-is-a-lot-to-gain-from-learning-how-to-code&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is a lot to gain from learning how to code&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;our coding program&lt;/a&gt; and revamp your career with impressive new skills.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Luke Stenis decided to quit marketing and learn how to code. Ready why, and how that decision has changed his life:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Choose a Coding Bootcamp that Teaches You More Than Just Code</title><link href="/blog/web-development/choose-a-coding-bootcamp-that-teaches-you-more-than-just-code/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Choose a Coding Bootcamp that Teaches You More Than Just Code" /><published>2019-04-13T18:57:29+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T18:57:29+00:00</updated><id>/blog/web-development/choose-a-coding-bootcamp-that-teaches-you-more-than-just-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/web-development/choose-a-coding-bootcamp-that-teaches-you-more-than-just-code/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethanstenis/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke Stenis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;graduated from Austin Coding Academy’s Full Stack Web Development program in 2016. Upon graduating, Luke landed a role as an “Implementation Engineer” with Austin-based content production company,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invodo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. During his time at Invodo, Luke also worked as an instructor at ACA, teaching the 10-week “Intro to Web Development” course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke currently works in Salt Lake City, Utah, as a “Digital Analytics Implementation Engineer” with&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PluralSight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been involved with Austin Coding Academy since its inception many, many moons ago. I’ve taken the coding bootcamp journey both as a student and as an instructor, and I’ve helped class after class of students go from complete novices to completely job-ready in the course of nine months, with varying degrees of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might surprise you, but in most cases the students with the best coding chops didn’t necessarily land the best gig upon graduating our program. Now don’t get me wrong, all Austin Coding Academy graduates are good hires, but in the dawn of our program, some students lacked a full understanding of what it truly takes to be a successful web developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Austin Coding Academy, we practice what we preach: &lt;strong&gt;Never stop learning&lt;/strong&gt;. We analyzed what was helping some students transition more successfully into a junior web development role, and what was causing some to stumble out of the gate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we found was that software companies, start-ups, and tech giants also desire candidates with a certain combination of soft skills. We were teaching the hard skills – coding languages, concepts, and techniques – but we needed to put more emphasis on soft skills like collaboration and critical-thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Junior web developers who are proficient in these three soft skills find success and are able to accelerate their coding career faster than even the best technical developers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;teamwork--leadership-skills&quot;&gt;Teamwork &amp;amp; Leadership Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started applying for dev jobs, my mentor gave me sage wisdom: walk through the engineering area - if developers are sitting silently in rows of cubicles with headphones on, turn and walk away. Great software is usually not written by one person, but by a team. A web development team is made up of different types of people in different types of roles, and sometimes collaboration and teamwork is loud… and messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most developers will also collaborate cross-departmentally throughout their project cycles, with needs to sync with designers, marketers, copywriters, or even managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the first day of class, students are placed into learning groups where they collaborate and work together on their first website project outside of class. We have found that students who collaborate and compromise well with others thrive in group work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the course of our 10-week classes, students who are successful also have a firm grasp on their time management. While we pride ourselves on a flexible program you can complete without quitting your day job, the coursework is no joke. You will need to hone your time management skills down to a science in order to master this soft skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;critical-thinking-and-problem-solving-skills&quot;&gt;Critical-Thinking and Problem-Solving Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most educational resources for coding follows the same process - choose a language to learn, teach you the syntax, and dive into concepts and theories. What it won’t teach you is how to solve problems or design the process for an entire project, which is why most of us learn how to code in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve already started learning to code, you know that it’s not easy. Part of the reason is that code is actually a tool, not a goal. To really learn how to code effectively, start by finding a problem to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve designed our coursework and classroom environment to help students develop the skills they need to properly assess a problem, conduct thorough online research, and design logic (and code) that solves the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;branding-and-marketing-skills&quot;&gt;Branding and Marketing Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want a (better) career in tech? Good, but you are not alone. Folks are flocking to the web development field and competition for jobs can be stiff. The problem I’ve seen is that most junior web developers don’t know how to or don’t even realize they need to be actively marketing themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I transitioned into web development, I spent a decade developing and running marketing campaigns. Here are the three soft skills we teach in tandem with code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bonus-build-your-personal-brand&quot;&gt;Bonus: Build Your Personal Brand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branding is about establishing a consistent message about yourself that is recognized by some repeated stimulus (online profiles, resume, portfolio) which when seen reminds the reader of the message. You may have a logo of your initials or a “doing business as” name you want to be identified as professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you are transitioning from a salesperson to web developer, you want to position yourself as a Junior Web Developer transitioning from a sales background. It will be imperative that you spin your past experience to support any soft skills you can gained from sales that are applicable to your new career. Here are a couple quick tips to help you with that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-a-consistent-online-presence&quot;&gt;Create a Consistent Online Presence:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve established your branding, positioning, and consistent messaging, make sure it’s used in your online portfolio, social media profiles, and any resumes you have living on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, use the same profile picture for Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, etc. Keep your posts professionally-minded - if you can be found on Facebook by your name, it’s a safe bet every recruiter or hiring manager has seen your photos from Cinco De Mayo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;build-your-network--off-line&quot;&gt;Build Your Network – Off-line&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re on LinkedIn and have a great network built-up online. That’s a great start! But now the hard part: Networking in real life!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best jobs I’ve gotten in my career and every good opportunity has been a result of someone in my network either bringing an opportunity to me or helping me get my foot in the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are looking for a job, you are essentially trying to sell yourself to someone. That may be great for the student who was a former salesperson, but not for everyone else. The next time you are trying to land a new gig, wouldn’t it be nice if you could just reach out to someone you know rather than sending cold emails or making cold calls?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a network isn’t hard but it does take effort. You should have the mindset of always networking. Every new person you meet, every person you interact with online is potentially someone who can become part of your network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, our students already have a head start on the first day of class. Not only do students have a robust network of current students, they also have access to our pool of alumni mentors and a non-stop events calendar of networking events and field trips to startups and tech companies around the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t just teach you how to code at Austin Coding Academy, we also teach you the soft skills you need to succeed in the diverse environment of a web development job. If you are interested in learning both the hard and soft skills necessary for a coding career, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;ACA’s course offerings.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get started learning how to code and much more with Austin Coding Academy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fill out an application to reserve your spot in the next class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Software companies, start-ups, and tech giants aren't just looking for coders. Junior web developers who are proficient in these three soft skills find success and are able to accelerate their coding career faster than even the best technical developers:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Awesome Apps You Can Create with C#</title><link href="/blog/2017/05/17/5-awesome-apps-you-can-create-with-c-sharp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Awesome Apps You Can Create with C#" /><published>2019-04-13T18:16:59+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T18:16:59+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/05/17/5-awesome-apps-you-can-create-with-c</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/05/17/5-awesome-apps-you-can-create-with-c-sharp/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is written by Austin Coding Academy graduate and former instructor, Luke Stenis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethanstenis/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke Stenis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;graduated from Austin Coding Academy’s Full Stack Web Development program in 2016. Upon graduating, Luke landed a role as an Implementation Engineer with Austin-based content production company,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invodo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. During his time at Invodo, Luke also worked as an instructor at ACA, teaching the 10-week “Intro to Web Development” course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke currently works in Salt Lake City, Utah, as a Digital Analytics Implementation Engineer with&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PluralSight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curious about what the C# programming language can do? Here is a short introduction to C# and five amazing apps you can build with this technology stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;language-in-the-key-of-c&quot;&gt;Language in the Key of C#&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# (pronounced See-Sharp) is a popular and modern programming language created by Microsoft in 2000 alongside their .NET framework. They wanted a more flexible language to build a variety of secure and robust modern applications for Windows, web servers, tablets, and phones. It is now arguably one of the most valuable programming languages in the world to know, and even had a mascot named Andy, who has now since retired in the green pastures of Mascot Hills, Florida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# is an object-oriented programming language that is commonly used with Microsoft’s .NET framework. Many of the advantages and features of C# are tied closely to .NET, which is why we teach them together in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/csharp/&quot;&gt;C# courses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# applications and programs run on top of the .NET framework, so that whatever you create can take advantage of the services and programming interfaces that the framework provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These programming interfaces include the ability to save information in a database, read information from an XML file, as well as cryptography, configuration, network communications and all the basic core features that nearly every application or program needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-you-should-learn-c&quot;&gt;Why You Should Learn C#&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# is a useful and flexible language with very expressive syntax that is easy and simple to learn. It shares many similarities with other object-oriented languages, and if you are also familiar with C, C++, or Java, you should pick it up very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of third party apps in the Windows app store are written in C#, and is widely considered the future of Windows application distribution. In short, C# has a very bright future within the Windows universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being productive in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indeed.com/jobs?q=C%23+Net+Developer&amp;amp;l=Texas&quot;&gt;C# can also land you a job&lt;/a&gt;. The U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) is predicting that between 2014 - 2024, employment of software developers is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/software-developers.htm&quot;&gt;projected to grow 17 percent from 2014 to 2024&lt;/a&gt;, much faster than the average for all occupations. The median annual wage for software developers was&lt;a href=&quot;https://money.usnews.com/careers/best-jobs/software-developer/salary&quot;&gt; $101,790 in 2017.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# jobs are abundant and pay well, and if you are fluent in C# and the .NET framework, you can create some awesome technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-can-create-with-c&quot;&gt;What You Can Create with C#&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use C# to build just about anything: business applications, games, web apps, and mobile/tablet apps. Here are five awesome applications you can build with C# code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-video-games&quot;&gt;1. Video Games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# is extremely popular in many sectors of the gaming industry. You can use C# to quickly develop games for Windows, Android, iOS, and Mac OS X. One of the most popular game-developing platforms is Unity, and C# is one of the most common and easiest programming languages you can use in the Unity environment. A few games built in Unity using C# are: Bastion, Shadowrun Returns, Rust, Wasteland 2, and Hearthstone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in developing video games, learning C# and becoming a C# Unity Developer is a popular and successful path for many video game developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-anti-hacking-software&quot;&gt;2. Anti-Hacking Software&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world now rich in cyber attacks, major hacks, and an urgent need to keep sensitive information safe, it comes as no surprise that companies, government, and financial institutions are scrambling to bulk with their cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter software developer stage left. These entities are bulking up their development teams with engineers strong in C# .NET technology to build and improve security software that keeps the likes of Wikileaks, Anonymous, and any potential ransomware from maliciously hacking into their and - sometimes - your data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-windows-apps-ie-microsoft-office-skype-photoshop&quot;&gt;3. Windows Apps (i.e.: Microsoft Office, Skype, Photoshop)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should come as no surprise that Microsoft’s C# and .NET framework is used primarily to create Windows client applications. Today, Windows Forms and Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) are two major technologies used to develop client applications. (link ‘used to… applications”: &lt;a href=&quot;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb655895&quot; title=&quot;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb655895&quot;&gt;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb655895&lt;/a&gt;(v=vs.90).aspx)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;examples-of-windows-applications&quot;&gt;Examples of Windows Applications:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel and so on)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet Explorer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skype&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual Studio 2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQL Server 2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paintbrush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that you won’t be developing for just Windows computers. You can write applications using the C# codebase to run on both Windows and Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-mobile-apps&quot;&gt;4. Mobile Apps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# is regarded in many development circles as the best language for mobile app development. You can build native mobile apps for multiple platforms – Android, iOS, and Windows devices – on a shared C# codebase. Yes, this means you are also creating an app that works and looks awesome on an iPhone, thanks to Xamarin, a framework that uses native API calls and native platform controls. (Link for “Xamarin”: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xamarin.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://www.xamarin.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.xamarin.com/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-few-examples-of-mobile-apps-written-in-c&quot;&gt;A few examples of mobile apps written in C#:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Insightly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pinterest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tableau&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The World Bank&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cinemark&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NBCUniversal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FoxSports&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aviva&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taxfyle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-windows-store-apps&quot;&gt;5. Windows Store Apps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows store apps were introduced by Windows 8, which coincides with the rise of C#’s popularity. Coincidence? I’ll let you be the judge. Windows store apps are different than mobile app development, and are built primarily using C# and XAML. XAML is used to build app screens and C# is used to run in the backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These apps have features like Touch, messages, tile and swipe, and work on all Windows devices - PCs, tablet, phones, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-to-learn-c-and-the-net-framework&quot;&gt;Where to Learn C# and the .NET Framework&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# and the .NET framework are a very mature and powerful technologies that enable you to create applications compatible across any device or operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are looking to change careers or coding languages, learning how to code C# opens up endless possibilities for your job prospects, app ideas and project scope. With the demand for C# developers on the rise over the next decade, there is no better time to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We teach this very technology at Austin Coding Academy. If you are interested in learning how to code C#, check out ACA’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/csharp/&quot;&gt;C# curriculum&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fill out an application to reserve your spot in the next class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Curious about what the C# programming language can do? Here is a short introduction to C# and five amazing apps you can build with this technology stack.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Free Coding Websites for Beginners: Learn How to Code without the Cost</title><link href="/blog/web-development/5-free-coding-websites-for-beginners/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Free Coding Websites for Beginners: Learn How to Code without the Cost" /><published>2019-04-13T03:43:48+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T03:43:48+00:00</updated><id>/blog/web-development/5-free-coding-websites-for-beginners-learn-how-to-code-without-the-cost</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/web-development/5-free-coding-websites-for-beginners/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethanstenis/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke Stenis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;graduated from Austin Coding Academy’s Full Stack Web Development program in 2016. Upon graduating, Luke landed a role as an “Implementation Engineer” with Austin-based content production company,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invodo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. During his time at Invodo, Luke also worked as an instructor at ACA, teaching the 10-week “Intro to Web Development” course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke currently works in Salt Lake City, Utah, as a “Digital Analytics Implementation Engineer” with&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PluralSight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article will cover some great coding websites for beginners and where to find them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has turning points in their lives, and many times we don’t realize we’ve made them until we are well down the road. Other times, we face a tough decision knowing full well that it could take us down two distinctly different paths, altering our lives all together and sending significant ripples through the space-time continuum, opening new dimensions that expose humanity to an otherwise oblivious and belligerent alien race, who in turn decide our planet is perfect for a new galactic freeway-side diner… and you’re on the menu! No pressure, homie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I digress. At this time last year, I faced a tough decision in my life. I was laid off, with a young family, and a burnt-out candle of a career. I spent the last eight years in Austin’s digital marketing scene, but it wasn’t satisfying, like that feeling you get sitting silently in a public restroom reflecting upon your regrettable choice of Chinese food, all the while listening to the guy in the stall next to you talk to his mother on his cell phone… “You’re a grown man, Chuck!” Get me outta here…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind was thirsty for a new challenge, something that balanced creativity, critical thinking, and a technically-sustainable skill. I wanted a new career path that was rewarding, not only financially but intellectually as well. I wanted to create and build stuff on the internet. I had taught myself basic HTML at past jobs – editing email templates with new images, copy, and updating simple styling. After a few meet-ups, online chats and coffee talks within my professional network, I was convinced that learning how to code was a big part of my answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step from there was to look for a more structured learning model, but I was unemployed so it needed to be cheap. Or free. Luckily, there are now ways to get introduced to computer programming without the cost of attending a University or intensive trade school. Many coding websites for beginners now offer free lessons and tutorials for learning how to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are looking to advance your career, supplement your skill set, or just love to learn, these five websites below offer instant and interactive courses to teach you programming languages… for free. Trust me, I’m not only a sponsor (not really), I’m also a member (really)…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;codecademy&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/&quot;&gt;CODECADEMY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By far the most well-known of the coding websites for beginners on this list, Codecademy.com offers well-structured, interactive courses covering the basics in Web Fundamentals, JavaScript, JQuery, Python, PHP, Ruby and APIs. This site is meant to expand a new developer’s vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside each course, you are given simple-to-understand instructions, helpful tips, and a user-friendly console to test out if your code is acceptable. If you make mistakes, you are given an error message and hints for completing each lesson. It’s like having an instructor looking over your shoulder the entire time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest part of Codecademy is that all the courses are free to use, but they do offer premium account level for additional projects and advanced tutorials. The site is great for a beginner looking for the structure of traditional coursework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code-avengers&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeavengers.com/&quot;&gt;CODE AVENGERS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code Avengers specifically designs their courses to appeal to all ages, so you know that they are going to be fun to work through. When you start a new course, you are asked a few simple questions to better tailor the tutorial to your learning environment, and you can choose whether to use video or text tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, they only offer HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Python, but they offer courses specifically designed to teach you how to build web pages, apps, or games as the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is great for beginners who want to be entertained as they learn. Honestly, who doesn’t?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code-school&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeschool.com/&quot;&gt;CODE SCHOOL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve worked through Codecademy or Code Avengers, I recommend checking out Code School. They offer more in-depth coursework that provides a clear path and more masterful grasp on each language. Definitely one of our best coding websites for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, you can choose one of four paths for becoming an expert:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HTML/CSS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iOS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly all the courses are packed full of well-written screencasts and polished design. The challenges that follow each lesson aren’t for the weak-willed, so consider yourself warned. Luckily there are hints to help you along the way. While most courses are free, some will prompted you to upgrade to a premium account in order to finish the entire course. For a small subscription fee, you get access to all the courses across the entire site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;treehouse&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/&quot;&gt;TREEHOUSE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like to master big concepts by building real projects, such as a responsive website, WordPress theme or application, Treehouse is a great place to learn programming with a purpose. You can build a foundation of knowledge in their vast offering of courses with a video + quiz format, each broken out into stages or modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you get past the first stage, however, you will be prompted to upgrade to a premium account for a small subscription fee. If you are serious about your coding chops at this point, this is a good investment as you get access to all 650+ videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lyndacom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lynda.com/&quot;&gt;LYNDA.COM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I lied to you… Lynda.com might be the most well-known site on this list. Please forgive me. Do we need to hug it out? No? Good. As you may know, Lynda.com is now owned and run by LinkedIn.com, so if you choose this route, consider wearing pants when logged in. Or not…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know or will soon find out, learning a programming language is like getting a tattoo, once you get one, you want to be covered in ink from head to toe by the end of the month… but it never happens. If you want to fall down an endless well of programming languages on Lynda.com, it CAN happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynda.com offers over 121 programming languages, 400 different courses and nearly 18,000 video tutorials for their Web Developer track alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy shenanigans, Batman, all that for free?! Well, not exactly. You can try it out with a free 10-day trial and get unlimited access to their coursework and featured experts. If you want to make a small investment in continuous learning, check out Lynda.com as an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t get a tattoo on there, but you can permanently “ink” some serious language knowledge in your brain. While this is definitely one of the better coding websites for beginners, this route is definitely for someone who has a developed a little chops and looking to take their coding game to 11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;learn-how-to-code-today-save-the-universe-tomorrow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LEARN HOW TO CODE TODAY, SAVE THE UNIVERSE TOMORROW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are looking to advance your career, supplement your skill set, or just love to learn, these five coding websites for beginners offer instant and interactive courses to teach you programming languages like HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, PHP, and Ruby. From videos, screencasts and tutorials, you will be taught best practices by industry professionals and programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows, it could be your first step toward mastering a programming language, changing your entire life, meeting the person of your dreams, raising a few unicorns, and possibly saving the entire “frakking” universe…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Whether you are looking to advance your career, supplement your skill set, or just love to learn, these five websites below offer instant and interactive courses to teach you programming languages… for free.</summary></entry></feed>